

ROMAN LOBKO

♠ Norway, Oslo

+4793944025

☑ roomen817@gmail.com

Ambitious self-taught software developer with experience in both backendand frontend development. Very curious and quick to learn new technologies and concepts. I appreciate teamwork, always happy to help others, as well as to learn from my colleagues. Creative problem solver, experienced in creating clean and reusable code for client-server applications.

SKILLS		LANGUAGE	
Java Core	Kotlin	Ukrainian	Native
Spring Boot with	Flyway Spring Security Real-time Interpreting Interpersonal Comunications	Russian	C2
Data, Web, Security, JPA		English	C1
PostgreSQL		8	B2
Docker Compose		Norwegian	DZ
Decetic		Japanese	N4-N3

EXPERIENCE

React.js

Full Stack Developer jan. 2024 - now

Romny Veteran Support, Romny, Ukraine (remote)

'Romny Veteran Support' - is an organization that helps former soldiers and veterans reintegrate into society. I am fully developing and continuously updating a website with all underlying infrastructure. Main stack is Java + Spring Boot, PostgreSQL for REST API and React.js for frontend with additional tools like Flyway for database migrations, as an example.

Interpreter for Public Services

feb. 2024 - now

Tolkenett & HeroTolk, Norway

Currently working at two agencies and providing oral real-time interpretations mainly for public services and healthcare institutions. Languages used in the job are Ukrainian, Russian, English and Norwegian.

Office Manager Assistant

mar. 2023 - aug. 2023

Bain & Company, Oslo

Worked well in a team and provided support and guidance to colleagues, as well as ensured overall order at the workplace. Had helped the office manager with everyday tasks and duties.

References are available on request

EDUCATION

Norwegian Intensive Course oct. 2022 - jun. 2023
Kuben videregående skole, Oslo

Computer Sciences, Bachelor (*unfinished due to war*) sep. 2020 - feb. 2022 Sumy State University, Sumy

Java Core Course jan. 2021 - sep. 2022

Sumy State University, Sumy

Fine Arts, Decorative Arts and Restoration, Junior Specialist
Sumy Professional College of Arts and Culture, Sumy
sep. 2019 - jul. 2023